<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CyberSecrets</title>
    <link>https://aibelkingslayer.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CyberSecrets</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://aibelkingslayer.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a Lightweight Python SIEM with Discord Notifications</title>
      <link>https://aibelkingslayer.github.io/posts/siem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aibelkingslayer.github.io/posts/siem/</guid>
      <description>Building a Lightweight Python SIEM with Discord Notifications 🧠 What is SIEM? SIEM stands for Security Information and Event Management. It is a system that collects, analyzes, and correlates security event data from various sources — like operating systems, applications, and network devices — in real time.&#xA;A SIEM helps:&#xA;🔍 Detect suspicious activity and threats 🧾 Maintain audit trails for compliance 🚨 Alert security teams about incidents 📊 Visualize security trends across systems Traditional enterprise SIEMs (like Splunk, QRadar, or Microsoft Sentinel) are powerful but often complex and expensive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My OSCP Journey</title>
      <link>https://aibelkingslayer.github.io/posts/my-oscp-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aibelkingslayer.github.io/posts/my-oscp-journey/</guid>
      <description>What is OSCP The Offensive Security Certified Professional (OSCP) is a highly regarded certification in the field of cybersecurity, offered by Offensive Security. It is designed to test a candidate’s ability to think critically and apply practical penetration testing skills in real-world scenarios. The OSCP certification is especially valued among cybersecurity professionals, as it demonstrates hands-on expertise in ethical hacking and penetration testing.&#xA;Key Highlights of OSCP: Practical Focus: Unlike many theoretical certifications, OSCP emphasizes hands-on skills.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
